Now we're going to cover the stakeholder
engagement assessment matrix.
So I didn't mention this in
communications.
So you will find this in your PIMBAC on
page 521 and 522.
We've covered this pretty well in your
slides and what we're going to cover now.
So we're planning stakeholder engagement
here.
So we need to know each stakeholder.
We'd have all the names.
Are they unaware?
Where?
Unaware of our project?
Are they resistant?
So we'll put C, where each is currently.
That's what C stands for, currently.
Are they unaware that the project even
exists?
Resistance.
A lot are resistant.
Don't want the project to happen.
Or they might even seek failure for your
project.
We need to know those people.
Neutral.
They don't really care.
Supportive.
They support.
the project they want it to succeed and
then we have leading actively engaged in
ensuring project success so this typically
is someone who has some power so
supportive these are like cheerleaders
leading those are called project champions
they can pull other people
to support the project so
they are leading ensuring
the project will be successful.
So again, we start with each stakeholder.
Where are they currently?
And then D desired where we want them to
be.
So ideally, we want everybody to come over
to support our project.
And then again, if they have power,
ideally we want them over here to lead.
Ensure project success.
get others to support the project.
So this again, I mentioned this in
communications.
The difference between current
and desired will determine the
communications needed to
engage the stakeholders effectively.
So this unaware person, we obviously have
to communicate with them quite a bit.
We need them to know we have a project.
B, you'll probably have
quite a few people in the
resistant column because
most people don't like change.
Scares them.
All right.
So you will find quite a few people will
resist the project.
So we need to communicate
with them, show them the
benefits of the project to
get them over to our side.
Neutral, at least they won't hurt us.
But ideally, we want them to support.
or lead to ensure the project succeeds.